# ARNAUD DÉCOLASSE

**FULL-STACK DEVELOPER** 

Following a Master's degree in computer science, I now have 15 years of experience as software engineer. I worked in companies of various sizes and domains, in France and in the United States. I mostly developed in Java environments on the back-end side, but I also have some experiences on the front-end using JS frameworks. On top of my full-stack skills, I have used extensively Agile and DevOps concepts during my different assignments. Recently, I've been promoted to leaderships roles (tech lead, manager) inside development teams, where I organized the way of working and made important architectural and technical decisions.



#### **DETAILS**

**PHONE** 

(+33) 06 98 75 59 91

**EMAIL** 

arnaud.decolasse@gmail.com

**ONLINE RESUME** 

adecolasse.com/en

**ADDRESS** 

Paris, France

### **SKILLS**

JAVA/KOTLIN

AGILE/DEVOPS

**REST API** 

DB/SQL

REACT/NODE

GRAPHOL

**CLOUD AWS** 

PEOPLE MANAGEMENT

PROJECT MANAGEMENT

PYTHON/SCRIPTING

## **EXPERIENCE**

**Full-Stack Developer** 

2023

TAAP, Expedia Group | Paris

During my last year at Traveldoo, I contributed on two Expedia projects to compensate for the decreasing activity. I worked first on REST and GraphQL APIs inside an AWS environment, and then on the NodeJS/React front-end applications used by all Expedia's sites. I collaborated with Expedia teams, as would have done a freelance developer, facing a new and complex technical context that I had to demystify before I could make significant contributions.

Senior Engineering Manager

2020 - 2023

Traveldoo, Expedia Group | Paris

Leader of a 5 to 9 people team developing the expense and administration applications at Traveldoo. Beside my manager role, I largely contributed to the developments and the technical evolution of the project, specifically on the REST microservices migration.

**Full-Stack Developer** 

2015 - 2020

Traveldoo, Expedia Group | Paris

Full-stack developer in the agile development team for the expense applications at Traveldoo. I worked on all layers of the application: back-end, front-end, batch. I progressively took on a technical leadership role contributing on the new microservices architecture and the Ci/Cd migration.

**Integration Developer** 

2013 - 2015

Sefas USA, Groupe Docapost | Boston

Integration developer on ADF (Automated Document Factory) technologies. Product customization for the customers' needs. Creation of workflows to handle documents creation, merging, processing, printing and mailing. Python and Java languages.

**Full-Stack Developer** 

2011 - 2013

Bouygues Telecom | Paris

Full-stack developer on the middle-office application (Gallium) managing millions of mobile phone's clients and contracts. Conception and development leader on new versions, quality and assurance tests, support and bug fixes in the production version.

Java and Flex technologies.

## **EDUCATION**

MASTER'S DEGREE, Computer Science

2006 - 2008

Université Paris Cité

Grade: "Mention Bien", Option: Information Systems

BACHELOR'S DEGREE,

Computer Science

2005 - 2006

Université Paris Sorbonne

